Some researchers had the tiny human
brains you can grow from stem cells
train each other by giving them either
reward or punishment until they behave
normally. This is indeed really weird.
Yes, you can grow tiny human brains from
stem cells. Yes, you can have them run
computation. And yes, they can interact
with each other. You can even put them
together like Legos and they'll act as
one unit. It's just more brain forbrain.
Because they tend to work better when
they're in groups, they are also tasked
with training each other. They have
relatively short lives, although some
people have been able to keep them alive
for a year or more. Most of them live 60
to 90 days. So, if you have 16 to a chip
like some companies are doing, you're
going to need to have the old ones come
in and train the new ones. That's what
they did. They set them up in groups of
three. There was a doctor agent that
would monitor a healthy agent and that
would tell it what normaly looks like.
Then they would look at a patient agent.
This might be one that's displaying some
unusual behaviors or it could be a brand
new one in the system. It would deliver
rewards if it were behaving
appropriately and it would deliver
something like disordered electric
shocks if it wasn't. Yes, it could in
fact train the new agent pretty
effectively. And if you're wondering how
they're communicating with the computer,
well, they're on a multi-elerode array.
This is something that can record neural
spiking patterns and then deliver
feedback so that the brain organoid
knows what's going on around it. It's
kind of a form of sensation. It's
actually not that different from what
you have going on with your own body.
You have sensation. You have light
hitting your eyes that's being
translated into electrical signals that
your brain can receive and your brain
will sort it out so it's meaningful.
Similarly, the electrical signals are
sorted by a computer. So, it can be
given to the brain organoid so they can
decipher it. They did something similar
with a card game where organoids would
be players and then they would have a
judge. The judge would look at what the
players got and decide whether to give
them a reward or a punishment. They
respond to both, so they do naturally
progress towards trying to win the game.
Rewards for brain organoids can include
things like dopamine are just ordered
signals or in some of the papers that
I've read with embodying them in game
world, they will give them continuous
unpleasant electric shocks until they do
something right and then they get peace
from the hellscape. But from what I've
read, they tend to do better with both
reward and punishment rather than one or
the other. One of the interesting
findings that's been seen in several
different labs is that complex brain
organoids do better. You would think
that just one type of cell would be
appropriate. Maybe we had one kind of
cell in our brain that's responsible for
cognition, but no, they need ones that
are involved in both short-term and
long-term memory. And brain organoids
tend to do better when they have some
kind of feedback. It's a literal brain
in a vat. So having some stimulation is
going to allow the little organoids to
do something. They have a job. They can
grow around that job and they can get
better at it. They're not conscious.
They may be sentient and that is an
argument, but they're just floods of
brain. And I think they're really cool
and kind of spooky, but I don't think
what we're seeing yet is real real
cognition. The simulations are quite
complex. It's a biohybrid computer. It's
working between AI and the actual
tissue. I think the message behind it is
that when we have brain organoids that
are coming in to do a job, new ones can
be trained by the older ones. I don't
think this has a whole lot of
applications to human medicine, but I
don't know. We can find out.